[
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "The thousands of people striped the roads Thursday in a posting of solidarity anti-government.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Among the demonstrators was Mestache Vardshvna, 23, of the Western coast of Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "\"We try to obtain the attention of our government,\" it said.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "\"It is important, thus I took leave of work to be part of this important event.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "\"It was one of much which used their power of free speech to express their concern with the current lack of transparency of government with public moneys.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "\"They must realize that we know what they make,\" additional Vardshvna.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "\"You cannot simply steal our money and to think you can leave with it.\"The",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "posters with coloured images of Elian Karel and Juliana Vann were recalls of the heavy toll already paid by chiefs and the innocent ones.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Juliana Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "Karel was the former chief of the guards of Kronos before his untimely death in 2009.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "Its death, thought with being a murder by, encouraged much cancel gatherings to bring the message of the guards of Kronos to the public.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "Juliana Vann died in 1998 of the cancer caused by environmental toxins in its drinking water.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Juliana Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 0,
    "sentence_index": 11,
    "sentence": "She had just turned ten years.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 1,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "The president and CEO of GAStech international Sten Sanjorge, Jr. can add another description to his name: billionaire.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge, Jr.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 1,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "And not only one billionaire, almost a billionaire surplus of twice like international sold shares of GAStech in a first public call to the saving.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 1,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "International GAStech, founded in 1961 by Sten Sanjorge, Sr., produces approximately 5 million cubic meters of gas daily from the curve of Tiskele of site to its drilling of GAStech - of Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge, Sr.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 1,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "As for the particular conditions of the classification: Stake of S 51% of Sanjorge Jr. it \"with the company is worth $1.96 billion; Stake of Beatriz Fluss it\" (widowed of Fluss hank of cofounder of company) 33% is worth  $1.27 billion.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Fluss",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 1,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "Not to feel sorry for the executives of GAStech - of Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 1,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "The classifications prove that GAStech - the executives of Kronos gained of the $327.25 collective million of the lately invested shares including $96.25 million for CFO Ingrid Barranco,CIO Ada Campo-Corrente, and Orhan Strum.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Orhan Strum",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 1,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "The environmental adviser of safety Willem Vasco-Pais also gained $38.5 million.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "The new pleas campaign in the horizon to maintain liquidity.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The agencies of the aid have noticed that the monetary necessities and of the food have increased everywhere and that they can not be able to solve basic necessities.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "The office of the O.N.U for the coordination of humanitarian subjects says that 15 million people of remain needing vital merchandize and services, because the number and the severity of crisis have given rise to a deficiency of the \"food, healthcare, and the access to sustenances.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "\"A",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "new group of the aid, Singapur THAT TOOK CARE OF has formed recently in answer to the conflict in Kosovo.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "Singapur THAT TOOK CARE OF has sent five missions to Kosovo to provide movable medical aid.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "Also they have sent a effort of the mobilization of bottoms in collaboration with the governments of Malaysia.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "\"We are stopped ready to help, but the financing is difficult to find,\" the indicated Dr Mahmed.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Dr Mahmed",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "\"As much it is necessary but as much it has been last already.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "\"They damaged to thirteen people Tuesday in Izmit, Turkey, as people filled up a convoy of the relevaci髇 of the government, the civil employees this.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 11,
    "sentence": "They absolutely fear 20,000 earthquake people both that have happened east year.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 12,
    "sentence": "Singapur THAT TOOK CARE OF has sent to equipment from the relevaci髇 to Turkey.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 14,
    "sentence": "Health for all the attended medical equipment of the emergency ad hoc during the earthquake of September in central Taiwan that measured 7,3 in the scale of Richter.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 16,
    "sentence": "\"Never 閞amos insurances they directed if us to the most desperate locations.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 17,
    "sentence": "Soon we worked of medicines and bottoms to support our equipment of the aid and had to return to house.\"",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 18,
    "sentence": "Whereas the disclosed global press on 2500 people was killed and 100,000 buildings were destroyed, the local press disclosed people felt they correctly took care of that it for and declined aid of the relevaci髇.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 2,
    "sentence_index": 19,
    "sentence": "The global report of the organization of the disaster of the emergency its members is making all she be able to obtain the aid to traverse to the victims of the earthquake, but they need enormous injections the bottoms to do so.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 3,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Friday early after four years of diminishing health after an important heart attack, Sten Sanjorge, SR. died morning.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 3,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Sanjorge, SR., 65, of Centrum, Tethys were president Emeritus of international GAStech have establishedthe company in 1961.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Centrum",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Emeritus",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 3,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Beside its role in international GAStech the President of the Council of management of the chamber of the center and member was of the Council of the hospital of the children of the center of administrators.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 3,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "Sten a champion for the children of Tethys, the aforesaid hospital president Willem Gracias has always been.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Willem Gracias",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 3,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "He was a truth clerk LEADER and worked infinitely to float our forward institution.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 3,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "Sten will become really missed and we ask that the everyone Sanjorge family prayed for.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 3,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "Sanjorge, SR. are survived by its woman Ingrid Sanjorge and its son Sten Sanjorge, Jr.Large in this world has been extinguished slightly, still he pours still a shade, aforesaid Sanjorge Jr. vowed.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ingrid Sanjorge",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sanjorge Jr.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 3,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "I to lead ahead a renewed vision and a dignity to which living and the work my father to our company with will honor.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "NOTE:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "This article is the second in a series, reprinted with permission from the Homeland Illumination.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Bodrogi has farmed soybeans his entire life, as did his father and their fathers.\"We've worked the land for a long time - maybe 200 years, maybe a bit more,\" Henk Bodrogi told me as he picked over a container of bolts, searching for the right size.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Henk Bodrogi",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "It took a while to figure out, then one of the city officers figured out to call in a water specialist.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "When they tested it they said the water was contaminated.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "\"The water specialist turned out to be the international agency \"Wellness For All\", an international agency with a mission to bring healthy water to communities distressed by natural disasters, draught and - coincidentally - oil and gas development.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "Reynolds agreed to speak to me for a few minutes between meetings about their work in Elodis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "The Elodis drinking water comes from the Tiskele River, as does all the water for farming, so we looked for a source upstream.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "The toxins are forming a subsurface plume that seeps into the Tiskele River from which the residents of Elodis draw their drinking water and irrigation for the crops.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "\"\"When we didn't make headway with GAStech,\" Reynolds continued, \"the community leaders decided to approach the government of Kronos for assistance.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "Per our policy -and with permission from the Elodis leaders - we published the test results in an official public document.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 4,
    "sentence_index": 11,
    "sentence": "The Elodis leaders then approached the government officials as citizens of a Kronesian community armed with the scientific analysis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 5,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "The Minister for health Cesare Nespola announced today that its organization would study complaints of the abnormal questions of health in the sectors surrounding the site of drill of curve of Tiskele.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cesare Nespola",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tiskele",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 5,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Said Nespola minister, \"we do not have any reason to believe that drilling with the curve of Tiskele had like consequence any contamination of external water of well or in the area.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nespola",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tiskele",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 5,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "However, I believe that it is important as minister of health to make diligence and to study the reports of the disease close to the suburbs of Elodis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 5,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "To take care of our people is my priority of the number one.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 5,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "\"In relative news, a press release of the office of Nespola proclaimed that its office granted a license to practice medicine with a oncologist of Tethys, making him the first oncologist authorized in the history of Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 5,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "Dr. Ronald Gerald will be resident at the hospital general of Abila.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ronald Gerald",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 6,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "One nine years - the old boy at the beginning survived the accident and had been stolen at the hospital of the children of Abila, but was declared deceased on the arrival.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 6,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The police force says that they have a driver of 25 year old truck in the guard with the prison of Elodis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 6,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "Auxiliary police chief Adian Koppolis of police force described the scene like \"terrifying\".",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Adian Koppolis",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 6,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "He said nine years - the old boy proved to wander around the site of accidents.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 6,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "\"It is tragic that nobody finally survived.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 6,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "The roads outside here can be unfair when you are not constantly vigilant while driving,\" it said.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 6,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "It noted that the truck passed in the intersection when the car had the right of the manner.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 7,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "A long tense day of conflicting reports and confusing information has come to an end.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 7,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Edvard Vann, a GAStech - Kronos security guard who was interrogated and released after 6 hours, gave the indication that the Protectors of Kronos were involved or at least suspected as being the perpetrators behind today's events.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Edvard Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 8,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "1532.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 8,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "An employee of Kronos - of GAStech that leaves the construction of the centers who refused in order to supply a name has said that a brace of unknown people was in the posterior part of the conference room in which the reunion of GAStech this morning has happened.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 8,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Unknown people that lurking around to the reunion room \"she was not employ you of GAStech\" and \"it has been dressed in the black clothing, watching in the previous ones.\"",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 9,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Update 1:00 PM:  Police have come and gone from the GAStech building, but up to this point no GAStech employees have left the building.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 9,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "We still have no official word on why the police are present.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 10,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "1018 - A fire alarm has gone off at GAStech headquarters.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 10,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "People are evacuating the building, and so far no sign of Sanjorge or his executive staff.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 10,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Officials have asked reporters to move away from the building to allow the fire department access.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 10,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "This has the flavor of yet another media ploy to avoid confrontation from the people of Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 10,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "20 Jan 2014",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 11,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Update, 3:05 PM:  A police P2o has left the scene, but others remain to the external part to fix the construction while others are still in the construction.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 11,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "There is much speculation approximately their activities, but the police has still to answer to our questions for information.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 12,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "A nine-year old boy initially survived the crash and had been flown to Abila Children's Hospital, but was declared dead on arrival.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 12,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Police say they have a 25 year old truck driver in custody at the Elodis jail.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 13,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "1025 - Up to now no test of smoke or fire has been marked.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 13,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The fire unit has to arrive hardly.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 13,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "20 gen. 2014",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 14,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "A rally of hundreds of protestors allied with the \"Protectors of Kronos\" movement turned to violence today as angry activists vented their displeasure on the innocent citizens of Abila after hearing the news of POK leader Elian Karel's death.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "pok",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Elian Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 14,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The POK assembly began peacefully enough with the usual chanted slogans and waving of protest signs, but then one young rabble-rouser grabbed a bullhorn and began inciting the crowd to violence.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 15,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "1744 - The means relationships are coming in how much a sure number of employees of GAStech have been rob you.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 15,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The identity of the passengers on the mystery jet that has left today more from the airport of Abila remains unknown.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 16,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "At the request of the citizens of Elodis, Wellness for All has published a report on the impact of gas drilling operations on water quality and public health.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 17,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "By 8 am had the local time, movement security copy on both sides of the ports.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 17,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "Swinging, sang protesters  protest songs, are including this  country, songs of the farmer and the weavers of our birth countryThen arresting protesters POK started the federal police force, moved themselves they in a neat manner in waiting police force van, which sings the complete time.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "In a touching ceremony Wednesday leaders of the activist group Protectors of Kronos paid tribute to their fallen leader, Elian Karel, who was murdered on 19 June 2009 while being illegally detained in a Kronos jail.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Elian Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "\"Today we gather to remember Elian Karel,\" Silvia Marek told the rapt assembly, many of whom held up white candles in Karel's honor.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Silvia Marek",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "\"Elian was born on an Elodis farm not 40 minutes from here, to Jeroen and Antaura Karel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jeroen",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Antaura Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "He grew up with the specter of death all around him.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "By the time Elian was 17 many of his family members and friends were battling constant illness, including his neighbor 10-year old Juliana Vann.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Juliana Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "\"Marek paused a moment to allow the cries of \"Remember Juliana!\" to fade.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Juliana",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "Elian knew his would be a difficult journey.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "He had watched his father, Jeroen and the founder of the POK, Henk Bodrogi walk the very path he would tread.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jeroen",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Henk Bodrogi",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 11,
    "sentence": "\"\"Elian's journey ended three years ago today.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 12,
    "sentence": "But his dream did not die with him.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 13,
    "sentence": "And it is that vision of a healthy and prosperous future for all we are here today to honor.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 14,
    "sentence": "\"Over",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 15,
    "sentence": "the course of the afternoon several other speakers paid tribute to not only Elian, but all who have been victims of the environmental catastrophe brought about by greed and corruption of public officials.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 16,
    "sentence": "The gathering was marred only by the aggravating presence of Abila police in riot gear.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 18,
    "sentence_index": 17,
    "sentence": "The police agitated many of the crowd, causing them to have to leave the assembly rather than be assailed with batons and pepper spray.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 19,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "ABILA, Kronos - Elian Karel, the charismatic LEADER of the guards of Kronos, was arrested today on charges of tax evaluation.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 19,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Michale Kraft, the lawyer of Karel, released a declaration claiming that the charges which are levelled against its customer false were and that he hoped its customer is delivered of police force preservation at the end of the week.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Michale Kraft",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 19,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Answered the declaration to the spokesman Adrien Carman of the police force by Kraft, explaining, I think M. Kraft the seriousness of the situation of its customer have underestimated.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Adrien Carman",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "M. Kraft",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 19,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "We have had dense its group since some time.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 19,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "followedOnly previous month, the group of Karel for violating incident responsible that was entrance to the hoofdkwartier GAStech - Kronos blocked.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 19,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "President and CEO Sten Sanjorge, Jr. of GAStech convicts POK as terrorists.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 20,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "A collection of hundreds of protestors which is united with the guards of movement Kronos which is twisted today to violence since the angry activists their dissatisfaction on the innocent citizens of Abila after hearing the news of POK the death of leader Elian Karel.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Elian Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 20,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Karel, which had waited for test for tax evasion, were found dead in its morning of prison cell yesterday.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 20,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "The assembly POK started peacefully enough with usual chanted slogans and undulating protest signs, but when rabble-rouser one youngsters started seized bullhorn and the calling mob to violence.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 20,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "The mob break windows and vandalized shops fires determined on the Siopa area, in the streets, and bluntest with police force.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 20,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "The extra police forces answered to contain chaos and they were forced rubber balls and use tear gas to spread the mob.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 20,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "The office of president Kapelou's released a declaration concerning the collection, explaining, this type will not forgive violence to become.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 20,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "Destruction and violence are no manner peace and reach change - these things are in opposition to each other.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 20,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "The guards of Kronos must resume peaceful resources; all other approaches are not justify.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 21,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "1506 - the police has begun to leave the centers of GAStech.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 21,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The officials have refused to answer to the questions of all the reporter that they leave the scene.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 21,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Some vehicles of the police are remained behind.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 21,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "Presumablly the remaining officials are interviewing employs of GAStech who still remain inside of the construction of the company.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 21,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "The cord of the police still remains around to the building of GAStech.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Heavies of the government obstructed the free speech - yet again - of the members of the protectors of the group of the activist of Kronos yesterday in a legal demonstration in the fields of the curve of Tiskele.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tiskele",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The five activists of POK had collected in front of the doors to the facility of the operations of the gas of GAStech that he perforated to cause to public conscience the contaminated river of Tiskele that has caused problems of health to the residents of Elodis.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "The present people disclose that the demonstration had begun Pacific with the five members of POK that walked forwards and backwards through way, singing \"remembers Julian\" and \"not more of poison\".",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "An eyewitness said that when the doors were opened to allow that the vehicles of the company of GAStech leave the facility the moved demonstrators to a side.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "The witnesses apparently agree that at the same time the vehicles with the government of the seal of Kronos lead to the doors, gliding to incorporate the facility.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "\"Era all the very civil one for above until then,\" Griffith Mabel, resident of Elodis that had left to support the POK said.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "\"The opened doors, the POK people moved and the cars expelled.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "That one is when stranger obtained.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "The cars stopped in means of the way for no reason.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "\"Another eyewitness, farmer Charley Normand de Elodis adds, \"Yes, the POK individuals requested that the conductors moved pleasant, but the conductors of GAStech did not pay attention to them.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "They had his windows down, so he was not as they could not hear them.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 11,
    "sentence": "\"The",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 12,
    "sentence": "renters of the vehicles of the government left and assembled of altercation.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 13,
    "sentence": "The event sequence gets to be confused at this point.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 14,
    "sentence": "Some witnesses indicate the instigadas discussions the conductors of GAStech with protestors, and others think that the officials of the government began to intimidate the demonstrators of the way.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 15,
    "sentence": "\"It is to people in the cars of the government were police,\" Mabel says.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Mabel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 16,
    "sentence": "\"He used the uniforms and had currencies.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 17,
    "sentence": "\"Onlookers says that the three parties began to shout, and in a certain point the police of Kronos - of Abila-",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 18,
    "sentence": "it arrested five activists it probably transported and them to a jail of Elodis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 22,
    "sentence_index": 19,
    "sentence": "In spite of the repeated orders an interview, has not granted the access those arrested.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 23,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "An official declaration sent by Sten Sanjorge, president of the Jr and the CEO of international GASTech, condemns the protectors of Kronos like \"ileg韙imate\" and organization of the \"terrorist\".",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 23,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The declaration came in answer to the meeting of the protest of Wednesday by the POK in the headquarters of GAStech - of Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 23,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Rough 200 people collected in front of the mottos singing of the building of GAStech and the samples that shook that they alleged people have died the debt the results of the contamination of a site that it perforated of GAStech.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 23,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "Sanjorge Jr responded to the demands of will refr醤 of the contamination of GAStech, \"We have worked untiring to solve - if it did not exceed - the international standards of the health been suitable upon with the government of Kronos before nobodies and everything being perforated.\"Ten",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sanjorge Jr",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 23,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "demonstrators of POK were chained to the door of GAStech - Kronos except for entrance to the building.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 23,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "In very long Sanjorge Jr. of the declaration presents to his discussion, \"if a person is arranged to violate in deprived characteristic, if a person is arranged to be chained to a door to avoid that a business works, if a person is arranged to break windows and to burn the cars in her own city, then that person is arranged to make any thing.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 23,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "And if a person is arranged to make any thing to obtain her goal of the end who presses fear in the common citizen.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 23,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "I fear what he will do later because I fear which he is able.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 23,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "When a people group uses fear and the violence to obtain its goals of the end is only one word for them there and that word is terrorist.\"The",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 23,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "declaration concludes with Sanjorge Jr who demands that the government of the system of Kronos until assures \"not only the security my employees, only all the citizens of Kronos.\"",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sanjorge Jr",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 24,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The leader of a forbearant environmental activist group, Karel had started a brand of politics all his own, that propelled the POK into the spotlight of this island nation.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 24,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "Resurrecting the embers of the Juliana Vann campaign, the 10 year old girl who died from illnesses attributed to the government-favored GASTech corporation's industrial waste streams in 1998, Karel was arrested and thrown in jail following a POK-initiated human roadblock in front of GAStech headquarters in May.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GASTech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 24,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "The government of Kronos refuses comment on the circumstances of his death.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 24,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "Rather charismatic, Karel was able to inspire a crowd and draw attention to the POK social and political agenda.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 24,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "Once, after GAStech CEO Sten Sanjorge Jr. likened the POK to a terrorist group in a press interview, Karel  quipped, \"Sanjorge is a brilliant leader of GAStech.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge Jr.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 24,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "Do you know why he takes a ladder with him to the supermarket?",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 24,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "He heard that food prices in Abila are really high.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 24,
    "sentence_index": 11,
    "sentence": "\"However, his ability to engage ultimately with the strong armed Kronos government had never been clear.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 24,
    "sentence_index": 12,
    "sentence": "It is also unclear who will take his mantle in the POK now he is gone.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 25,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "The brazen day time assault on two peace officers by the POK is just another violent, terroristic act in a long string of such acts.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 26,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Update, 6:10 PM:  The executive jet of GAStech according to as reported it has arrived in Tethys bearing Sten Sanjorge Jr. some hours ago.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge Jr.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 26,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The jet has been resupplied of fuel quickly and then it has been left for the international airport of Abila with six civil employees of GAStech on board.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 27,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Today is the fifth anniversary of President Araullo's visionary plan to bring foreign investment to Kronos, a bold act that has reaped tremendous benefits for our fair country.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Araullo",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 27,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "These people claim that foreign investment is bad for our country, that it is diluting our culture and undermining our values.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 27,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "The hypocrisy of bringing in foreigners to tell us that opening our country to foreigners is bad for us is ludicrous and is obviously a sign of mental illness in those who oppose our modernization.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 28,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "A Protectors of Kronos demonstration in the streets of the Siopa district in downtown Abila resulted in numerous incidents of vandalism and opportunistic looting yesterday.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 28,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Crowd members spray painted the new POK logo on buildings and cars, broke shop windows, looted stores, and intimidated innocent bystanders.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 28,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "The police were forced to use tear gas and water cannons to disperse the group of hooligans.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 29,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "The Protectors of Kronos (POK) are suspected of kidnapping up to fourteen GAStech employees from their headquarters building earlier today.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 29,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Abila police quickly secured the building and interviewed the remaining GAStech employees.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 29,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "One employee, Edvard Vann of Abila, was questioned for hours because he shares a family name with several known POK members.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Edvard Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 29,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "Vann denied involvement with the POK and claimed to have no knowledge of the kidnapping.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 29,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "Tethyn federal law enforcement and representatives from the Tethyn Ministry of Foreign affairs flew to Kronos and were escorted to Abila police headquarters.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 30,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "850 21 January 2014 - DAY TWO of the event of GAStech - we are attending the news conference of unit of the police of Abila previewed for the 9:00.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 31,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Update, 6:30 PM:  The GAStech executive jet arrived at the airport.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 31,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The occupants were taken by limousine to the GAStech building.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 32,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Update, 6:40 PM:  There is the speculation that the personal of GAStech that they have arrived from Tethys are expert of emergency that they are helping the police with the search.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 33,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Thousands of people lined the roads on Thursday in a display of antigovernment solidarity.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 33,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Among the demonstrators was Mestache Vardshvna, 23, from the west coast of Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 33,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "\"We're trying to get the attention of our government,\" he told the Homeland Illumination.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 33,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "\"This is important, so I took time off from work to be a part of this important event.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 33,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "\"He was one of many who wielded their power of free speech to voice their concern with the current lack of government transparency with public monies.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 33,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "\"They need to be aware that we know what they're doing,\" added Vardshvna.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 33,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "Karel was the prior leader of the Protectors of Kronos before his premature death in 2009.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 33,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "His death, thought to be a murder by many, prompted annul rallies to bring the message of the Protectors of Kronos to the public.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 33,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "Juliana Vann died in 1998 of cancer caused by environmental toxins in her drinking water.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Juliana Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 33,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "She had just turned ten years old.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 34,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Last year spontaneous protests and riots broke out around Abila in response to the death of Elian Karel, a Protectors of Kronos (POK) activist.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 34,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Officials fear a repeat of last year's violent activities around the city on the upcoming anniversary of Karel's death on June 19.Government officials issued a brief statement assuring the people of Abila that their \"safety is of the utmost importance.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 34,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Groups like the Protectors of Kronos operate by fear, attempting to change lives and government through fear.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 34,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "The brief government statement ended there with a promise not to back down to protesters, if there are indeed protests.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 34,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "Hagar Awelon, a shop-owner in Siopa district of Abila heavily impacted by last year's events, responded to the government statement: \"They [Government of Kronos] must do more than they did last year.\"",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Hagar Awelon",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Pondo Reese, editor of the Elodis Weekly Journal, stands at his window, looking out toward the sun setting on the Tiskele River.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "I've asked him to tell me about the involvement of the government of Kronos in the deeply troubling account of a community's struggle for protection from those who should help them the most: their elected officials, against those who would poison their children and the country's food.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "\"It took a long time for anyone to respond,\" Reese tells me of their struggle.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "\"Henk Bodrogi - the man you met - didn't give up.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Henk Bodrogi",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "He called every department that could possibly be associated with our problem:  interior, justice, foreign affairs, health.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "Henk and a few other residents made several trips to Abila trying to get someone to listen.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "Finally, a sympathetic person from the Ministry of Health answered the door, so that's where we started.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "\"Reese then describes months of meetings at which the government officials demanded documents proving their case:  health and crop yield statistics, the scientific test results from Wellness For All, and medical records.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "\"It's been frustrating.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "We bring the documents they want, and then they want to confirm the results, or tell us to provide additional information or have closed door meetings.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 11,
    "sentence": "We're currently in the process of negotiating a date for a hearing at the Ministry of Health to present our petition for assistance.\"Has",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 12,
    "sentence": "it been worth it?\"You tell me,\" Reese nods out his window.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 13,
    "sentence": "I look over his shoulder to see a group of children kicking a soccer ball in the dust.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 35,
    "sentence_index": 14,
    "sentence": "\"What choice do we have?\"",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "<<Deleted picture: POK many demonstrations in the capital of Kronos van Abila>> have keptMost important tale remains the readingThe government of Kronos has explained the guards of Kronos a terrorist after in former days accusing of a deadly attack on politiehoofdkwartier these week groups himself.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos van Abila>>",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Spokesman Rufus Drymiau of the government announced the movement to, which will give more competence to the authorities on POK to burst.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Rufus Drymiau",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "He said that they belonged that to the group, it financed or is activities promoted punish under eyes would see.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "Most important tale remains the readingThe guards of KronosOldest and largest environment the activist organization of KronosSet up in 1997.Influenced by international groups such as Wellness for allThe political activism of mixtures with the environment workThe use of negatives of violence and supports democratic principlesSlogan: Justice for Juliana, a reference to 10 years - the old little girl Kronosian that as a result of government died environment pollution sponsoredThe decision was in reply to the bomb attack of Tuesday of politiehoofdkwartier in Abila, said he.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Juliana",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "Kronos were fulfilled with abomination from North to south by the dreadful crime POK devoted, M. Drymiau said.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "M. Drymiau",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "This was in context of dangerous escalation to violence against Kronos and Kronosians and a clear declaration by POK that it nothing knows then violence.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "It is not possible for Kronos the state nor Kronos people to terrorism present POK.LOCATION:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "Kronos will add Tethys which antiKronos will add Tethys which anti-terrorismeverdrag of 1998 of the decision had signed communicate, he.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "Verdedigers POKLOCATION: POK have denied the cause are of the attack, and the government Kronos of the intensification of kaderPOK have denied the cause are of the attack, and the government Kronos of the intensification of kader-omhooggaand the group care for people to be silent bring accused.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "A member POK told The Times that the decision of the government illegitimate was.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 11,
    "sentence": "He added: The protests, certainly.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 36,
    "sentence_index": 12,
    "sentence": "to continue",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 37,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "AWELON, CYNTHE / DOB:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 37,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "3/20/1981 / Time of Arrest: 0003 hrs / Accused of: DRUG PARAPHERNALIABLUMIAU, WILLEM / DOB:",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 37,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "9/20/1974 / Time of Arrest: 1500 hrs / Accused of: THEFT ALL OTHER-3RD DEGREEGUDENZ, KEL / DOB: 7/2/1995 / Time of Arrest: 1630 hrs / Accused of: FAILURE TO MAINTAIN CONTROL; DWLUHOLANDE, ANDA / DOB: 3/26/1981 / Time of Arrest: 0003 hrs / Accused of: IMPROPER BRAKE LIGHTKIBALIAU, IYAN / DOB: 4/3/1994 / Time of Arrest: 1500 hrs / Accused of: THEFT ALL OTHER-3RD DEGREEMORDECAI, FRANCISCO / DOB: 3/17/1971 / Time of Arrest: 2215 hrs / Accused of: PUBLIC INTOXICATION; POSSESSION OF CONTROLLED SUBSTANCE (Heroin)PEAIRS, MELSHA / DOB: 8/31/1952 / Time of Arrest: 1330 hrs / Accused of: FORGERYLOCATION: SALANIAU, FERDINAND / DOB:",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "DEGREEGUDENZ",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "DWLUHOLANDE",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "LIGHTKIBALIAU",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 37,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "2/17/1982 / Time of Arrest: 0832 hrs / Accused of: THEFT ALL OTHERSALANIAU, FERDINAND / DOB: 2/17/1982 / Time of Arrest: 0832 hrs / Accused of: THEFT ALL OTHER-3RD DEGREE;",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Today is the fifth anniversary of President Araullo's visionary plan to bring foreign investment to Kronos, a bold act that has reaped tremendous benefits for our fair country.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Araullo",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Today's Abila is a bustling metropolis full of new cars, new construction, gleaming office buildings, and modern conveniences.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Gone are the potholed streets, run-down factories, tired storefronts, and sad marketplaces of the past.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "Today's Abila is a city of industry, a place of commerce and investment, a place of opportunity and success.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "Prosperity has come to Kronos, and we are all the better for it.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "However, there are still those who wrongly think that prosperity is bad for us.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "These people claim that foreign investment is bad for our country, that it is diluting our culture and undermining our values.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "They claim that the foreigners are exploiting us for their own gain and that our government has little regard for the welfare of our people.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "They are so militant in their wrong-headed beliefs that they have fabricated claims that the foreign companies are poisoning our children with their technology.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "They have even gone so far as to have brought in foreign \"experts\" who claim to \"have our best interests at heart\" to help spread their agenda against progress and prosperity for our people.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 38,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "The hypocrisy of bringing in foreigners to tell us that opening our country to foreigners is bad for us is ludicrous and is obviously a sign of mental illness in those who oppose our modernization.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 39,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Update, 1:50 PM:  We have tried twenty more phone numbers at GAStech, but no one else has answered.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 39,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "We tried calling Mr. Strum's administrator again, but she did not answer the phone.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Strum",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 40,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Local GAStech executives Ingrid Barranco, Ada Campo-Corrente, Orhan Strum, and Willem Vasco-Pais and CEO Sten Sanjorge Jr. will attend a reception with government officials tomorrow following a business meeting at their headquarters building.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Ingrid Barranco",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Ada Campo-Corrente",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Orhan Strum",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge Jr.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 41,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "A motion became taxes at oil and gas the development with extra 10% raise reports today at the general meeting by a voice of 77 to 23.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 41,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The presented tax increase, which by minister of health Cesare Nespola is defended, had specific financing for health care, clean water projects, and supply health information for country areas.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Cesare Nespola",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 41,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Minister Nespola aforesaid of the poll of the assembly, I am disappointed by the poll, but the assembly feared that the increase of tax foreign investment in our energy sector would dissuade.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Nespola",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 41,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "This a developement is to my programme our rural help municipalities, but I am nothing as not permanent.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 41,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "My office will send a revised added tax measure to the assembly later on the year.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 41,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "Moreover, I will work with the office with president Kapelou's to restructure current gas and oil taxes assignment of funds of for rural health projects to provide.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kapelou",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 42,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "A press release from the Ministry of Interior today announced that the Tiskele Bend gas fields could be as much as 5 times larger than originally estimated.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 42,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "When we contacted Minister Sarto's office for comment, he said, \"We were astounded by the results of GAStech's recent survey of Tiskele Bend.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sarto",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 42,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "I mean, this is just huge for the people of Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 42,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "We have already undertaken several large improvement projects like the port expansion and the new hospital that we would not otherwise have been able to do because of the taxes we are seeing from our foreign investments.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 42,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "This news almost assures we'll be able to reap those same dividends for decades to come!\"It goes without saying that President Araullo's plan to lure foreign investment has been a defining moment in our history.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Araullo",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 42,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "One hopes that those who had been so shortsighted as to oppose his plan have finally come to their senses.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 42,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "We will say what they are too proud to say: Thank you, Mr. President.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 43,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "1732 - great part of the information has re-united from employs of GAStech that have been allowed to go from the point of the investigators of the police to a kidnapping of several employ you of GAStech.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 43,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "However, the civil employees have still not confirmed a kidnapping have happened.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 43,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "The number of employs lacking is indeterminant currently given the confusion to you more begins them with the false fire fire signaler.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 43,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "If to align, this is a escalation alarming of the violence for the group of the activist.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 44,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "Update, 2:00 PM:  A government automobile has been allowed with the perimeter of the police.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 44,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The occupant, that she seems to be an emergency civil employee, has been left in the construction.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 45,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "In a statement to the press today, government spokesman Rufus Drymiau said of the POK: \"they are justifiably a public threat due to violent demonstrations, opportunistic vandalism, and clashes with the police.\"",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Rufus Drymiau",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 46,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "After 52 years of being privately owned, Sten Sanjorge, Jr. is taking GAStech public.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge, Jr.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 46,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The company, founded in 1961 by Sten Sanjorge, Sr., said Monday it plans a stock offering that could place its value in the neighborhood of $3.75 billion.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge, Sr.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 47,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "ABILA, Kronos - president Araullo today announced the signature of an agreement between his government and the GAStech Tethys-based international for the development of the gas fields of the curve of Tiskele.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Araullo",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Tiskele",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 47,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "GAStech, under direction of the visionary Sten Sanjorge Jr, was granted the rights exclusive to perforate inside the governmental fields after being suitable the request of the government who 50% or more of the manual labor are citizen of Kronosian.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge Jr",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 47,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "President Araullo hailed the distribution of the signal like \"the principle of a new one was for our great country, of an era of the opportunity and the fortune for all.\"",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Araullo",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 47,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "Our sources in the Department of the Interior say us that the tax of 50% tax in the new exploration of the oil and the gas could render superior to $1 billion in fiscal income per year.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 47,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "This will allow that the government makes investments without precedents in the infrastructure, the medical care, and the education.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 48,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "A government investigation concluded that an accident between a GAStech vehicle and an Elodis family, which killed all four members of the Elodis family, was caused by driver error by the Elodis driver.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Elodis",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 48,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The spokesman Rufus Drymiau of the Kronos government said that research found the fatalaccident was started when the driver of Elodis crossed into oncoming traffic.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Rufus Drymiau",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 48,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "He succumbed to his injuries later at the hospital of Abila.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 48,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "In an exposure of the international wishes of GAStech of generosity of corporation to give the money to the remaining members of family.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 49,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "After a long day of conflicting and confusing information reports are still sketchy, but the story is beginning to come clear: a Kronos Government source has confirmed up to fourteen of GAStech International's employees may have been kidnapped at the company's headquarters in Abila.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos Government",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 49,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Much speculation remains regarding who was taken in the kidnapping.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 49,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Speculation includes whether or not GAStech International President and CEO Sten Sanjorge Jr. was the target given that GAStech International has yet to make a statement to the press.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Sten Sanjorge Jr.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 49,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "Speculation about the motivation behind the kidnapping has also been rampant due to the recent GAStech IPO.At this time no one has claimed responsibility for the kidnapping.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 49,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "Edvard Vann, a GAStech - Kronos security guard who was interrogated and released after 6 hours, indicated the Protectors of Kronos were suspected as being the perpetrators behind today's events.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Edvard Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 49,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "A GAStech International senior security executive has been on site to support the investigation, aiding the Abila Police Department and Kronos Government officials.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos Government",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 49,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "January 20th was GAStech's annual corporate meeting.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 49,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "At some point while company officers were transitioning from the main office to a Kronos Government reception the abductions took place.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos Government",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 49,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "Abila Fire Department trucks were dispatched to GAStech - Kronos headquarters around 10:00 this morning local Kronos time to respond to a fire alarm.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 50,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "For roughly 6 hours GAStech - Kronos employee Edvard Vann was interrogated by Kronos Police and Government officials before being released at 17:00 this evening.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Edvard Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 50,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The apparent confusion stems from the similarity between his name and that of a Protector of Kronos member.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 50,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "Vann, a security guard for GAStech, was furious, stating, \"I have nothing to do whatsoever with any members of the terrorist group POK.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 50,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "I know no one from Elodis.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 50,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "I was born here in Abila and I support my government and my president.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 50,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "Being accused and being interrogated for 6 hours as a terrorist POK member is one of the worst days of my life.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 50,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "Just because a person has the same name as a criminal does not make him a criminal.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 50,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "\"Though he was instructed not to communicate with the press Vann was adamant to stress his innocence.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 50,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "With some 14 GAStech employees still unaccounted for, one cannot blame the police or the government for not leaving any stone unturned.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "The thousands of demonstrators who take the flags that read \"remember Julian\" and singing \"we wished truth\" reunited in front of the morning of Saturday of the governmental offices of Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Julian",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "The demonstrators demanded an accounting of the yields of the then government of the fiscal incentives of president Araullo that were signed in law in 1993.Of ten years old Julian Vann died in 1998 of a disease caused by the contaminated water of the operations of GAStech.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Araullo",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Julian Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "She has made the icon heartrendering of a movement that has gained the aid from a end from Kronos to the other.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "\"They promised better works to Us, the new ways, healthcare better and a better standard to live,\" 20 years old protestor that declined to have its used name.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "\"All what I see is greater mansions for the ministers and a hospital that costs more to the adjustment than he can do.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "We will not accept that\"The protestor referred apparently to the general hospital of Abila constructed in 1997 with the money of the increasing yield of the foreign operations of the gas here in Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "The nonlucrative hospital has been having difficulty maintaining of its infrastructure, in spite of several made extensive restoration for years to replace the electrical systems and that drilled.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "\"The contracts all were given to the family and the cronies of the ministers,\" accuse 26 years - old Jon L., that traveled six hours to take care of the meeting of yesterday.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Jon L.",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "\"What we needed it is the transparency in our government.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "We need to know what happens to all the money that comes inside from these foreign companies.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "The leader Elian Karel of the protest dealed with the demonstrators in the park the city of Abila.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 11,
    "sentence": "Karel assumed the control the direction of POK of Henk Bodrogi, that to bad forced it health under the position.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Henk Bodrogi",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 12,
    "sentence": "Karel spoke eloquent on the principles of the campaign of POK like effort of the towns for the clean water, to the dynamic movement it has the improved transparency demanding turned and responsibility of the government.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 13,
    "sentence": "\"We are not requesting any unreasonable thing,\" Karel speaks enthusiastic to its ardent listeners.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 14,
    "sentence": "\"The only thing that we wished is to know are being used our taxes.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 15,
    "sentence": "We know that these corporations are generating benefits of the files to expenses of Kronos, but do not see no of the engaged improvements.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 16,
    "sentence": "The only thing that we wished is responsibility for that they died due to avarice, the corruption and the indifference of a that must protect.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 17,
    "sentence": "\"The",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 51,
    "sentence_index": 18,
    "sentence": "calls to the office of the president were not returned immediately.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 53,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "1545 UPDATE - These \"shadowy\" figures are at the center of what appears to be a kidnapping incident with the victims being the missing GAStech leadership.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 53,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "At this time we can only speculate on the number of people involved.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 53,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "In the confusion from the building evacuation an accurate count of GAStech employees is nearly impossible.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "With the third anniversary of Elian Karel's death approaching - former member of the Protectors of Kronos - the question is: who are the protesters?",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian Karel's",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "But not only who are they, what and why are they protesting?The Protectors of Kronos or POK were founded in 1997 by residents of rural Elodis on the advice of the now defunct Wellness for All (WFA), an international water safety group.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "pok",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "The POK was initiated to bring attention to the clean water issues surrounding Elodis to the Government of Kronos and the world.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "The POK asserts that GAStech International's Tiskele Bend natural gas drilling site is the source of both the contamination of drinking water as well as the destruction of the traditional farmland surrounding Elodis.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 4,
    "sentence": "In 1998, WFA performed testing on the water of Elodis finding high levels of benzene, toluene and xylene arsenic, barium, chromium, lead and selenium.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "xylene arsenic",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 5,
    "sentence": "The testing a subsequent statement released by WFA brought international attention and pressure on the government and GAStech to act.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "GAStech",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 6,
    "sentence": "However, with the fragmenting of WFA due to funding issues, the POK's demands were largely ignored and downplayed.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 7,
    "sentence": "Also in 1998, Juliana Vann, a previously healthy ten-year old girl died of a lingering illness, which WFA-funded doctors claimed was caused by water contamination.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Juliana Vann",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 8,
    "sentence": "The Government of Kronos officially refuted the claim citing the fragmentation of the WFA organization as evidence of an unreliable source not to be trusted.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 9,
    "sentence": "Regardless, Juliana became the POK's first martyr and has used Juliana's image on campaign literature ever since.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Juliana",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 10,
    "sentence": "The POK's second major martyr is Elian Karel, who died in 2009 while incarcerated of undetermined causes.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Elian Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 11,
    "sentence": "The POK asserts he was arrested on trumped up charges while the Government of Kronos contends he was a radical and violent activist engaged in tax evasion.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 12,
    "sentence": "Karel had been involved with the POK since its inception given that his father, Jeroen Karel, was an original member.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "Jeroen Karel",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 13,
    "sentence": "Elian Karel's death in 2009 was marked by spontaneous instances of protest around Abila.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Elian Karel's",
        "label": "PERSON"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 14,
    "sentence": "The anniversary of his death, June 19, has seen additional protests, demonstrations, riots, and violence.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 15,
    "sentence": "The POK has evolved from peaceful protests and demonstrations demanding government action to more violent activities including riots as they claim that the government has done little to nothing in addressing the contamination, poisonings, and deaths suffered by their people.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 54,
    "sentence_index": 16,
    "sentence": "As of 2011, the Government of Kronos has labeled the POK as a \"public threat\".",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      },
      {
        "text": "POK",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 55,
    "sentence_index": 0,
    "sentence": "The thousands of people aligned the ways Thursday in an exhibition of solidarity antigovernment.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 55,
    "sentence_index": 1,
    "sentence": "Between the demonstrators it was Mestache Vardshvna, 23, of the coast of the west of Kronos.",
    "entities": [
      {
        "text": "Mestache Vardshvna",
        "label": "PERSON"
      },
      {
        "text": "Kronos",
        "label": "ORG"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "articleID": 55,
    "sentence_index": 2,
    "sentence": "\"We are trying to obtain the attention of our government,\" he said.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 55,
    "sentence_index": 3,
    "sentence": "\"This is important, so I took time extinguished from the work to be a part of this important event.",
    "entities": []
  },
  {
    "articleID": 55,
    "sentence_index": 4,
